[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb3", "question": "What Big US East school took the cryptic name for its sports teams from the Greek word for \"what\"?", "answer": "Georgetown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2a", "question": "What lung disease killed Paul Cezanne a week after he caught a chill and collapsed while painting in the field?", "answer": "Pneumonia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65c0b1f3c0ead6880d60c", "question": "Who was called in the Bible \"the disciple who Jesus loved\"?", "answer": "John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f3", "question": "Whose remains were thrown into the Seine River on May 30, 1431?", "answer": "Joan of Arc's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d5", "question": "Which series of novels refer to its main character as \"The Last Gunslinger\"?", "answer": "The Dark Tower", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5902a0d3cad1ec93f27df771", "question": "How much larger is UK pint compared to the US pint?", "answer": "About 20%, or 95 mL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e94cc7ccba3ffe45786d7", "question": "What year did the programming language \"COBOL\" first appear, before being standardized in 1968?", "answer": "1959", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab1430baab681b09292171", "question": "What country is home to the automobile manufacturer ZAZ?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bf", "question": "What does a coleopterist study?", "answer": "Beetles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8d", "question": "What bread's name may come from German words meaning \"devil's fart\"?", "answer": "Pumpernickel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339321", "question": "In the movie \"Hangover\", what name did Alan use to refer to his circle of friends?", "answer": "The wolf pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a43f", "question": "Which country is home to the Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a000", "question": "What British TV series featured Eddie \"Fitz\" Fitzgerald and Jane \"Panhandle\" Penhaligon?", "answer": "Cracker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37acb0ada16518afdc05c", "question": "Who led the resistance against Italy in Ethiopia during World War II?", "answer": "Haile Selassie I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb58dd5dad637d903c8812", "question": "What is Bhutan's national sport?", "answer": "Archery -- It was born out of necessity as bows and arrows were used to repel Tibetans and British invaders in the 19th century.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb8", "question": "Besides corn, what's the other principal ingredient in succotash?", "answer": "Lima beans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e31", "question": "Who is Miguel Ferrer's mother?", "answer": "Rosemary Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6012185b63c99d48cd169af1", "question": "The first hockey pucks used in early outdoor hockey games were made of what?", "answer": "Frozen cow dung", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfe00dbb668d7dfe168b5c6", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Muswell Hillbillies\"?", "answer": "The Kinks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25ef516682715b82711cd6", "question": "What year did the Mayflower transport the first English Puritans to the New World?", "answer": "1620", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0dd", "question": "Who was Humphrey Bogarts 4th wife?\u00a0", "answer": "Lauren Bacall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe771d1eec85e375820b300", "question": "Which country hosts the world's highest marathon?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cdbb877e98cb97778a3a", "question": "In which European city would you find Orly airport?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a792", "question": "Trinidad and Tobago is part of which continent?", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce7", "question": "What Nobel Prize-winning author committed suicide by gunshot in 1961?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab1778baab681b09292182", "question": "What numbers appear on Donald Duck\u2019s car plate?", "answer": "313", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d0", "question": "Who directed the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Charles Walters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb1137e83c707845b210b", "question": "Which planet was discovered by mathematical prediction before it was directly observed?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980b", "question": "Which ballad by the band Poison is about a Vietnam veteran and the homeless?", "answer": "Something To Believe In", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a28", "question": "Who played Richard Nixon in the 1995 film \"Nixon\"?", "answer": "Anthony Hopkins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c299", "question": "What is the hardest substance in the human body?", "answer": "Enamel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd85", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Kamacuras?", "answer": "Praying mantis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918d", "question": "Which is the only one of the Seven Dwarfs without a beard?", "answer": "Dopey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab7", "question": "On Mount Rushmore, which one of the presidents is wearing a jacket?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010cabb0775fa611bce67fe", "question": "Emetophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Vomit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049cfccf93664eb10486ab", "question": "What is the more common name for the 1987 computer virus that was set to go off on Friday the 13th of every year?", "answer": "Jerusalem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88b", "question": "What does the Bark scale measure?", "answer": "Perceived loudness of sounds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f2", "question": "What US state has been governed by Evan Mecham and Bruce Babbitt?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c7fa877e98cb977789da", "question": "In which capital city would you find the Marley Museum?", "answer": "Kingston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8ccac94b094db915830a1", "question": "How many Oscars have been awarded from inception through the 88th Academy Awards?", "answer": "3,048", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbf", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in a guacamole?", "answer": "Avocadoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173e6544491cbd7c5a17b0", "question": "The Wright brothers originally ran what kind of business?", "answer": "Bicycle repair and design -- The name of their business was Wright Cycle Company.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca59", "question": "A light aircraft without an engine is called a what?", "answer": "Glider or a sailplane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddd9a6ce05a3942286da5", "question": "What American singer-songwriter wrote and first recorded the song \"Blue Suede Shoes\" in 1955?", "answer": "Carl Perkins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b907", "question": "How many times is a trains whistle blasted if it is about to move forward?", "answer": "two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a382", "question": "What is the capital of the Netherlands?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51bddff04d658268c9311", "question": "In the Bible, who sold his birthright because he was hungry?", "answer": "Esau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc22cec223966ae8f8872", "question": "Actor Veronica Cartwright reacting with genuine shock during the \"chest-bursting scene\" of which classic horror movie?", "answer": "\"Alien\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ced9877e98cb97778a47", "question": "What state is home to the Crazy Horse Memorial?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46b", "question": "Which duo was the first to reach the summit of Mount Everest in 1953?", "answer": "Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e4", "question": "In what country was the \"Michelin Guide\" first published in 1900?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3236bdbf195a31e15d73be", "question": "\"Oliver's Story\" was the sequel to which best-seller by Erich Segal?", "answer": "Love Story", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd970e223c87fd04dd15e49", "question": "What U.S. state was the first to ratify the Constitution?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338928", "question": "Which rock group charted \"Land of Confusion\" in 1986?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d7db2596a59cbdfbd3bb", "question": "What American folk hero was a real-life Tennessee congressman?", "answer": "Davy Crockett", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a7f6096f5f79087132fb42", "question": "In finance, what does \"QRM\" stand for?", "answer": "Quantitative Risk Management", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c953", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Draco?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad6", "question": "In which continent would you find the Lena River?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f95aea455722f97b22684d5", "question": "Which Star Wars character is the first to be partially named after director George Lucas\u2019 son?", "answer": "Dexter Jettster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffe4ba247818f5674af01b2", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I am no bird; and no net ensnares me; I am a free human being with an independent will.\"?", "answer": "\"Jane Eyre\" (Jane Eyre famously says this to Mr. Rochester, whom she loves, but claims she is still capable of leaving.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59db77ae0ab2c8f322317fed", "question": "Which holiday replaced Dominion Day in Canada?", "answer": "Canada Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe768e8eec85e375820b2a9", "question": "What is the record snowfall in Phoenix, Arizona?", "answer": "One inch", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be17", "question": "What's the most common \"singing membranophone\"?", "answer": "The kazoo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5d", "question": "How was the country of Belize known prior to 1973?", "answer": "British Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93a2a6bd93ce3a4e5f694", "question": "What do you call the application of science to criminal investigation?", "answer": "Forensic science", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b30d01dd7bf43be5e7a7", "question": "What US state is home to the Crazy Horse Memorial?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339320", "question": "What was the name of Bill and Ted's rock band in the movie \"Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure\"?", "answer": "Wild Stallions", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067dc4ff9c0647b50a8074", "question": "Which gaming franchise celebrated its 20th anniversary on February 27, 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f9f3740b707a806402fd725", "question": "What is often referred to as \"the powerhouse of the cell\"?", "answer": "The Mitochondrion, or mitochondria (plural)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d3", "question": "What former country was Martina Navratilova born in?", "answer": "Czechoslovakia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e1", "question": "What is a judo practitioner's Judogi?", "answer": "Uniform", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a298", "question": "In musical terms, what does \"Da capo\" mean?", "answer": "From the beginning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b830e662d71a5365101e", "question": "What is the name of the literary club founded by J.R.R. Tolkien while in Oxford as a professor?", "answer": "Inklings", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba69", "question": "In what year was Gettysburg National Military Park founded?", "answer": "1895", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b014", "question": "The Orient Express is a train route between what two cities?", "answer": "Paris and Istanbul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339818", "question": "What are the names of the five Planeteers from the TV show \"Captain Planet and The Planeteers\"?", "answer": "Kwame, Wheeler, Linka, Gi, and Ma-Ti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacb", "question": "What is the International Criminal Police Organization better known as?", "answer": "Interpol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42e", "question": "What period saw the first dinosaurs?", "answer": "Triassic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b7", "question": "In what year was the March of Dimes founded?", "answer": "1938", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d01", "question": "What Texas Instruments product does E.T. use to \"phone home\"?", "answer": "The Speak & Spell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c517", "question": "What is a cross between a blackberry and a raspberry?", "answer": "Boysenberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909caf5bb53d1af658864d4", "question": "What year did Hallmark made its first Christmas cards?", "answer": "1915", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16b", "question": "In which European city are the headquarters of OPEC?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e09", "question": "Which of the Bront\u00eb sisters wrote only a single novel?", "answer": "Emily", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecf", "question": "What animated film begins in Shiverpool, Antarctica?", "answer": "Surf's Up", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c547", "question": "Who averaged one invention patent for every two weeks of his working life?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe937706bd93ce3a4e5f66d", "question": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dogs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969e", "question": "Who played the role of Peachy Carnehan in the 1975 movie \"The Man Who Would Be King\"?", "answer": "Michael Caine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ef", "question": "Which classic science fiction author wrote \"The End of Eternity\", \"Pebble in the Sky\", and \"The Caves of Steel\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86d", "question": "Where in England is the Stonehenge monument located?", "answer": "Wiltshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ac", "question": "At least 21 fragments of which comet smashed into Jupiter in July of 1994?", "answer": "Shoemaker-Levy 9", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac33", "question": "Which side did Britain support in the US Civil War?", "answer": "The Confederacy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96c5a23c87fd04dd15e23", "question": "Which president appeared on a U.S. coin while he was still alive?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ddfffe83fe1f2a824b68", "question": "What conflict was instigated by Aristagoras of Miletus?", "answer": "Persian War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8c", "question": "What is the capital of Senegal?", "answer": "Dakar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c202", "question": "Which country hosted the 1900 Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e90906d333868d34d750", "question": "What country were cars invented in?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d29", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"The Stratton Story\"?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b093", "question": "What large amphitheater in Rome was opened to showcase gladiator combat?", "answer": "The Colosseum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f7493a9e54d890926f6fa", "question": "In Texas, it\u2019s illegal to swear in front of what?", "answer": "A corpse", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af64", "question": "What year was the company \"Hewlett-Packard\" founded?", "answer": "1939", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388aa", "question": "What is the last name of brothers Dmitri, Ivan, Alyosha and Smerdyakov?", "answer": "Karamazov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca6", "question": "Who wrote \"The Power of Positive Thinking\", first published in 1952?", "answer": "Norman Vincent Peale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f71", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Jim Douglas?", "answer": "Herbie, the Love Bug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523e1d736d4be723796b4b", "question": "In which Canadian city would you find the largest mall in North America?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c214877e98cb97778985", "question": "What is the smallest borough of New York City by land area?", "answer": "Manhattan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596dfd319616e6c6d4eba4f4", "question": "What is a baby swan called?", "answer": "A Cygnet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a914", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Leavenworth?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec83eaec223966ae8f87fa", "question": "The musical group 3T are all relatives of which legendary pop musician?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f5efff048f679a45aad9", "question": "What physicist discovered that a wave's frequency changes when the source and the observer are in motion relative to one another?", "answer": "Christian Doppler", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab3", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Denmark?", "answer": "Mute swan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d4d22b42d4a3561a9efc", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", which employee of Mrs. Parker was framed with stealing $850,000 from Senator Chalmers?", "answer": "Samantha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe5", "question": "Who are Kambei, Katsuhiro, Gorobei, Shichiroji, Kyuzo, Heihachi, and Kikuchiyo?", "answer": "The Seven Samurai", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a8b090aac110e4167091", "question": "In the North American market, what is the difference between hard and sweet cider?", "answer": "Hard cider is alcoholic while sweet cider is not", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc8420078d18506ae1fe489", "question": "What species is the tallest tree in the world?", "answer": "California Redwood", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb81", "question": "What Christian denomination was begun by John Wesley in 1738?", "answer": "Methodist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd4", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"tsunami\"?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd6b", "question": "In photography, what kind of \"number\" is used to measure lens speed?", "answer": "f", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc48", "question": "Who was Andre Agassi's greatest tennis rival in the 1990s?", "answer": "Pete Sampras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8fb", "question": "The Bitterroot Range of the Rockies is located on the border between what two US states?", "answer": "Idaho and Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef60d76ce05a3942286e4c", "question": "Which comic book company was founded as Timely Publications?", "answer": "Marvel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febac757e83c707845b20ee", "question": "Which spider spins the world\u2019s biggest web?", "answer": "Darwin's bark spider", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d1159a4fea7fe947a22268", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa0", "question": "What musical won a record breaking 12 Tony Awards?", "answer": "The Producers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a739", "question": "Klamath Lake is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93d236bd93ce3a4e5f6af", "question": "What is Jupiter's largest moon?", "answer": "Ganymede", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4b", "question": "What is the name of Captain Nemo's submarine in \"Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea\"?", "answer": "The Nautilus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb1b37e83c707845b210e", "question": "A group of otters is called what?", "answer": "A raft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6017370a44491cbd7c5a1783", "question": "Hugin and Munin were raven spirits that accompanied which Nordic figure?", "answer": "The ravens Hugin and Munin (meaning \"thought\" and \"memory\") are said to sit on the shoulders of the Nordic god Odin.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c784", "question": "Aeolian processes pertain to the study of what weather activity?", "answer": "Winds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6d", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Bo and Luke Duke?", "answer": "The General Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7354beec85e375820b248", "question": "Who said, \u201cThere are a terrible lot of lies going about the world, and the worst of it is that half of them are true.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecdb5fec223966ae8f88f4", "question": "What movie marked the Hollywood film debut of William Shatner?", "answer": "\"The Brothers Karamazov\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee4", "question": "Which cabinet post did Winston Churchill hold between 1924 and 1929?", "answer": "Chancellor of the Exchequer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93c216bd93ce3a4e5f6aa", "question": "The bark of which tree is fireproof?", "answer": "Redwoods", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a95a", "question": "Which European country replaced the Markka with the Euro?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9a", "question": "Who gave Impressionism its name with his 1873 painting \"Impression, Sunrise\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60077fd2bd51d85e222ab640", "question": "What was the official diagnosis when van Gogh was hospitalized in 1888?", "answer": "When Van Gogh was hospitalized on Christmas Eve 1888 in Ales, his official diagnosis was \"acute mania with generalised delirium\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8d", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Gettysburg\" based on?", "answer": "The Killer Angels", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a498", "question": "Into which sea does the Nile river flow?", "answer": "The Mediterranean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590087785304ceedb84e8997", "question": "Until World War II, solid blocks of what was commonly used as currency in Siberia?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a5", "question": "What car lost 96 percent of its sales in the four years after the publication of Ralph Nader's \"Unsafe at Any Speed\"?", "answer": "Chevrolet Corvair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3867c73aa70ea0b70ad0", "question": "Which US state gets its name from a made-up word?", "answer": " Idaho (Mining lobbyist George M. Willing told Congress \"Idaho\" was a Native American phrase for \"gem of the mountains\". He made it up.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6a", "question": "Who replaces Professor Snape as Potions Master at Hogwarts?", "answer": "Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd2", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"honcho\"?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56a", "question": "Which automaker opened the first foreign plant in the US?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe90a3c01dd7bf43be5e898", "question": "An octopus can fit through any hole larger than its what?", "answer": "Its beak", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a479", "question": "In which Irish city is Shannon airport?", "answer": "Shannon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad5", "question": "How many zeroes are in the number one trillion?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b323", "question": "Who served as the head of the Soviet Union from 1922 to 1924?", "answer": "Vladimir Lenin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93b446bd93ce3a4e5f6a1", "question": "According to Galileo's biographer, what tower did he climb to prove his \"Law of Falling Objects\" theory?", "answer": "Tower of Pisa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4bd849076251badbeac9", "question": "What country's declaration of war triggered the start of World War I?", "answer": "After Bosnian Serb Gavrilo Princip assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand, Austria-Hungary declared war on Serbia in July 1914.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bcc", "question": "What did God create on the fourth day?", "answer": "The Sun, the Moon and the Stars", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90c", "question": "What major river runs through Florence?", "answer": "Arno", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2db", "question": "What country was called Northern Rhodesia until 1984?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77d", "question": "What teacher taught Helen Keller the manual alphabet and Braille?", "answer": "Anne Sullivan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8af2a01dd7bf43be5e788", "question": "How much of the population is left-handed?", "answer": "10%", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d2", "question": "How does James Bond like his martinis?", "answer": "Shaken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4da", "question": "What is the largest country entirely within the Southern Hemisphere?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1f", "question": "What is the capital of Poland?", "answer": "Warsaw", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f3", "question": "What is Goldfinger\u2019s first name?", "answer": "Auric", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba4", "question": "What country is located immediately north of Sudan?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0b", "question": "What is the last word of the Bible?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c3e983aebfabb9c85d8a96a", "question": "Which novel by Michael Crichton was a best selling paperback in 1993?", "answer": "Jurassic Park", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05b", "question": "What is the name of Amy Winehouse's first album?", "answer": "Frank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e28", "question": "Who is Kate Hudson's mother?", "answer": "Goldie Hawn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a7", "question": "What important crop is the Rhine Valley in Germany known for growing?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008e05cf4f3bc4a292f8631", "question": "What artist said, \"Every child is an artist\"?", "answer": "Pablo Picasso (The full quote reads,\u00a0\"Every child is an artist, the problem is staying an artist when you grow up.\")", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6c", "question": "Who played the role of TV's J. J. Starbuck?", "answer": "Dale Robertson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d5", "question": "What musical is set at Rydell High?", "answer": "Grease", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd663a0a5bfecdd737e0852", "question": "How long does it take blood to circulate the vascular system?", "answer": "20 seconds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338995", "question": "Who was married to Andrew Lloyd Webber when he composed \"The Phantom of the Opera\" for her voice?", "answer": "Sarah Brightman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c176", "question": "What type of instrument is a Celesta?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad65", "question": "In 1701, who invented the seed-planting drill?", "answer": "Jethro Tull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c58", "question": "What year did singer Whitney Houston die?", "answer": "2012", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e8cdfe83fe1f2a824bdf", "question": "Which rebellious leader of the Catuvellauni tribe was caught and taken to Rome in AD 50, then pardoned by Emperor Claudius?", "answer": "Caractacus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa4", "question": "What musical is the sequel to \"The Phantom of the Opera\"?", "answer": "Love Never Dies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c854", "question": "What nation is home to the Komodo dragon?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c513", "question": "Which substance can you not eat, if you have celiac disease?", "answer": "Gluten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2dc", "question": "Avian flu in China led to 2006 price hikes in what piece of sporting equipment?", "answer": "Badminton birdies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133986b", "question": "In Disney's \"Cinderella\", how many evil Step-sisters does Cinderella have?", "answer": "2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe90a1401dd7bf43be5e895", "question": "Which 19th-century Englishwoman became the first qualified medical doctor?", "answer": "Elizabeth Garrett Anderson", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f1fdfe83fe1f2a824c18", "question": "What is the first of the four cups of wine diners are obligated to drink at the Passover Seder meant for?", "answer": "Kiddush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a8", "question": "How many stripes are there on the US flag?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of North Carolina?", "answer": "Raleigh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4d", "question": "What type of device was the first Sony-branded product, released in 1955?", "answer": "Transistor Radio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b9", "question": "Texas City is located at the mouth of what bay?", "answer": "Galveston Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae35", "question": "What sport did Gerald Ford play at the University of Michigan?", "answer": "Football", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ea81b24f84e0b9f9ffd5", "question": "Homichlophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fog or humidity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c35a7815febcc896f925e", "question": "In which country would you most likely find the traditional Mariachi bands?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f8", "question": "What lizard can be 10 feet long?", "answer": "The Komodo dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5eb73dbc5e259d7869087335", "question": "During the Kentucky Derby races, what fashion event is known as part southern tradition and part spectacle?", "answer": "The Hat Parade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8b", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Danny in \"City Slickers\"?", "answer": "Jake Gyllenhaal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecda82ec223966ae8f88e9", "question": "What film features a fight scene in which Bruce Lee breaks Jackie Chan's neck?", "answer": "Enter the Dragon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c5", "question": "Who had a No.1 hit song in 1998 with \"C'est la Vie\"?", "answer": "B*Witched", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b610", "question": "A \"Michigan Loader\" is what?", "answer": "Earth moving equipment", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the three-eyed fish named?", "answer": "Blinky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db77d30ab2c8f322317fef", "question": "What country does motor racing's Jacques Villeneuve come from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b359", "question": "How did Al Capone die?", "answer": "Syphilis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab94f486faa38a764be511", "question": "In the automotive world, what does the abbreviation DOHC mean?", "answer": "Dual OverHead Cam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c8d4fbde8045e48466e1", "question": "Why do some plants send chemical signals to bugs?", "answer": "Signal for help -- Leafy tobacco plants send a chemical signal to wasps, who will seek out caterpillars eating the leaves.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc0706ce05a3942286f08", "question": "Who starred as Rudy Baylor in the 1997 film \"Rainmaker\"?", "answer": "Matt Damon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924f", "question": "What movie's first batch of soap is made out of fat from liposuction clinics?", "answer": "Fight Club's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa3df6ce05a3942286eac", "question": "Which Oscar-winner studied opera as a teen?", "answer": "Meryl Streep", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a82", "question": "What female dog is the secret object of Underdog\u2019s affection?", "answer": "Sweet Polly Purebred", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96ee7ccba3ffe45786f4", "question": "A 8 to 12 mph wind on the Beaufort scale is called what?", "answer": "Gentle breeze", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cf", "question": "Who played the role of Julia Brougham in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Loretta Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7360deec85e375820b258", "question": "What was the name of the doctor who treated John Wilkes Booth's fractured leg after he shot President Lincoln?", "answer": "Dr. Samuel Mudd", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a936", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Monaco?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed7", "question": "The journey in Roald Dahl's \"James and the Giant Peach\" ends with the peach impaled on what?", "answer": "The Empire State Building", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49f", "question": "Which country were the 1920 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca26", "question": "Syncope is the medical name for what condition?", "answer": "Fainting", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdfb933003d27d341092bc2", "question": "Where is King Tut\u2019s tomb?", "answer": "Valley of the Kings", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fedd8976ce05a3942286d71", "question": "What is the required amount of years a player must be out of high school before being eligible to play in the NFL?", "answer": "Three years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3f", "question": "In Italian, the Mona Lisa is called what?", "answer": "La Giocondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ba", "question": "What was the name of the first album released by the 1990's German band \"Snap!\"?", "answer": "World Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c006", "question": "What name is given to a year with 366 days?", "answer": "Leap", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339759", "question": "Who directed Out Of Sight?", "answer": "Steven Soderbergh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b88", "question": "What Looney Toons cartoon character often used the catchphrase \"Thufferin' Thuccotash\"?", "answer": "Sylvester the cat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0e8df964118b2bb3809c7", "question": "The custom of sending cards, flowers, chocolates and gifts on Valentine's Day originated in which country?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3923ff048f679a45ab27", "question": "The metamorphism of what rock forms marble?", "answer": "Limestone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f975fe83fe1f2a824c33", "question": "What does the final day of Passover celebrate?", "answer": "The arrival of the Israelites to the Red Sea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a7", "question": "In what fictitious town does \"Invasion of the Body Snatchers\" take place?", "answer": "Hicksville, USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c897", "question": "Which of the main categories of cloud forms at the highest altitudes?", "answer": "Cirrus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b657", "question": "What company introduced the first radio with push-button tuning in 1927?", "answer": "Zenith", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff2db668d7dfe168b5b5", "question": "Which duo is credited with inventing the \"Spinning Frame\"?", "answer": "Richard Arkwright and John Kay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133951e", "question": "What was the name of Danny's gang in \"Grease\"?", "answer": "The Thunderbirds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a010", "question": "What TV show's famed \"puffy shirt\" is in the Smithsonian today?", "answer": "Seinfeld's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa5e36ce05a3942286ec5", "question": "What real American Revolution battle served as inspiration for the film \"The Patriot?\"", "answer": "The Battle of Cowpens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a18", "question": "What 2003 reality series starred a construction worker named Evan Marriott?", "answer": "Joe Millionaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067b3eff9c0647b50a8062", "question": "With what global issue does the 2016 Paris Agreement deal with?", "answer": "Climate change", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b8e2e662d71a53651029", "question": "The line \"All of this happened, more or less.\" starts what novel?", "answer": "\"Slaughterhouse-Five\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b845", "question": "What is a perfect score in bowling?", "answer": "300", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c316", "question": "What is one of pi's rational approximations?", "answer": "22/7", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc40", "question": "What nationality is tennis player Roger Federer?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76c", "question": "Diamond Head is a popular surfer destination off the coast of which US state?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f5655f33a95c66dc4fe756", "question": "What does a phrenologist measure?", "answer": "Skulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ae85e134007905755f79e86", "question": "In chronological order, what is the first book in the Chronicles of Narnia series?", "answer": "The Magician\u2019s Nephew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c997", "question": "What colour bill does a Greylag goose have?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975a", "question": "Whose music is featured in the musical movie Mamma Mia!?", "answer": "ABBA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c170", "question": "Karakul and Dorset are types of what?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd610e347d002c297e4ba", "question": "On what date is The Melbourne Cup traditionally held?", "answer": "The first Tuesday of November", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89b", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the Norse god of thunder?", "answer": "Thorium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25961b63e5727cf5a484d", "question": "Celine Dion's \"My Heart Will Go On\" song was featured as the main theme song to which 1990's movie?", "answer": "Titanic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601601cffe83fe1f2a824c62", "question": "What does the star on the top of a Christmas tree symbolize?", "answer": "This is symbolic of the \"Star of Bethlehem\", the same star the Magi are said to have seen.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35f", "question": "What volcanic peak can you see from Naples?", "answer": "Mount Vesuvius", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff2152b31a458464a93c45d", "question": "The \"pomsky\" dog breed is a mix between which two dogs?", "answer": "Siberian Husky and Pomeranian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b9", "question": "Who took the role of Lysander in the Disney version of \"A Midsummer Night's Dream\"?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c6f49076251badbead4", "question": "Who once owned the land on which Arlington National Cemetery is situated?", "answer": "Confederate General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a411", "question": "A person from North Carolina is properly known as a what?", "answer": "North Carolinian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab1b2b64fda37788a9a1dbd", "question": "What is the fear of darkness called?", "answer": "Scotophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85b", "question": "On which harbour is the Sydney Opera House located?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour", "category": "geography"}]